export const GENERALKNOWLEDGEINARTSA2017 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The technique of using dots in shading is",
A: "crisscrossing",
B: "smudging.",
C: "hatching.",
D: "stippling.",
answer: "D. stippling",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Perfect stability is indicated by a",
A: "curved line.",
B: "horizontal line.",
C: "diagonal line.",
D: "zigzag line.",
answer: "B. horizontal line",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. When variety is introduced in a work of art it reduces",
A: "boredom.",
B: "curiosity.",
C: "vigour.",
D: "vision.",
answer: "A. boredom",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Principles of design include",
A: "balance, rhythm and variety.",
B: "space, dot and harmony.",
C: "shape, form and colour.",
D: "texture, unity and line.",
answer: "A. balance, rhythm and variety",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. The black stool of the Ashanti’s is believed to embody the soul of the",
A: "ancestors.",
B: "children.",
C: "linguists.",
D: "women.",
answer: "A. ancestors",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Female tenderness, warmth and affection are symbolized by",
A: "concentric circles.",
B: "shooting star.",
C: "crescent moon.",
D: "zigzag lines",
answer: "C. crescent moon",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. String musical instruments are classified as",
A: "Aerophone",
B: "Idiophones",
C: "Chordophone",
D: "Membranophone",
answer: "C. Chordophone",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. A person who accepts challenges and tasks and complete them is referred to as",
A: "creative.",
B: "extrovert.",
C: "introvert.",
D: "superhuman.",
answer: "A. creative",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. A degree of surface roughness or smoothness is",
A: "design.",
B: "pattern.",
C: "print.",
D: "texture.",
answer: "D. texture",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. A print made by the silk screen process is.",
A: "flexography",
B: "letterpress.",
C: "intaglio.",
D: "serigraphy.",
answer: "D. serigraphy",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Inverse relief is also referred to as",
A: "bas relief.",
B: "medium relief.",
C: "low relief.",
D: "high relief.",
answer: "A. bas relief",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. The palette knife is mainly used for",
A: "cutting.",
B: "painting.",
C: "priming.",
D: "shaping.",
answer: "B. painting",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Drawing in charcoal is fixed with",
A: "lacquer.",
B: "oil.",
C: "petrol.",
D: "turpentine.",
answer: "A. lacquer",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Armature is to modeling as easel is to",
A: "carving.",
B: "casting.",
C: "Drawing",
D: "painting.",
answer: "D. painting",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Egyptians painted figures small and light in colour to represent",
A: "children.",
B: "royals.",
C: "Slaves",
D: "Women",
answer: "C. Slaves",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Identify the artist of the High Renaissance period in the following.",
A: "Giotto",
B: "Raphael",
C: "Masaccio",
D: "Van Gogh",
answer: "B. Raphael",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. The last step in appreciation is",
A: "criticism.",
B: "interpretation.",
C: "identification.",
D: "judgment.",
answer: "D. judgment",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. The time for gathering information in the creative process is the period of",
A: "incubation.",
B: "preparation.",
C: "perception.",
D: "verification.",
answer: "B. preparation",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Which of the following animals symbolizes’ reliability?",
A: "Hyena",
B: "Elephant .",
C: "Monkey",
D: "Leopard",
answer: "B. Elephant",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Visual artists create satire by means of",
A: "Anatomy",
B: "foreshortening.",
C: "caricature.",
D: "perspective.",
answer: "C. caricature",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. In nature, spider web are perceived as examples of",
A: "form.",
B: "lines.",
C: "shape.",
D: "space",
answer: "B. lines",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. The origins of indigenous Ghanaian arts are explained by",
A: "Anthropology",
B: "drama",
C: "ethnography.",
D: "myths.",
answer: "D. myths",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. The human body serves as a suitable support for",
A: "engraving.",
B: "etching.",
C: "painting.",
D: "scorching.",
answer: "C. painting",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Pointillism is a method of shading by way of",
A: "crisscrossing.",
B: "hatching.",
C: "cross-hatching.",
D: "stippling.",
answer: "D. stippling",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. In which of the following techniques are tesserae used?",
A: "Collage",
B: "Engraving",
C: "Mosaic",
D: "Printing",
answer: "C. Mosaic",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. The invention of cubism is attributed to",
A: "John Constable and Peter Reuben.",
B: "Pablo Picasso and George Braque.",
C: "Paul Cezanne and Vincent van Gogh.",
D: "Salvador Dali and Paul Gauguin.",
answer: "B. Pablo Picasso and George Braque",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. The Bundu helmet masks are worn during",
A: "child birth.",
B: "festivals.",
C: "initiation.",
D: "funerals.",
answer: "C. initiation",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Passing judgment on a work of art involves",
A: "appreciation.",
B: "history.",
C: "criticism.",
D: "therapy.",
answer: "C. criticism",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Tonal drawing involves the use of",
A: "hatching and cross-hatching.",
B: "light and shade.",
C: "sense of touch.",
D: "sense of sight.",
answer: "B. light and shade",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Which Ghanaian artist researched into Adinkra symbols and compiled them into a chart?",
A: "Ablade Glover",
B: "Saaka Acquaye",
C: "Kofi Antobam",
D: "Vincent Kofi",
answer: "C. Kofi Antobam",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Identify the art that was solely practiced by the indigenous Ghanaian women.",
A: "Carving",
B: "Pottery",
C: "Smiting .",
D: "Weaving",
answer: "B. Pottery",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Which of the following is a dry medium?",
A: "Gouache",
B: "Oil colour",
C: "Pastel",
D: "Poster colour",
answer: "C. Pastel",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Identify a fabric in the following",
A: "cotton.",
B: "tap",
C: "selvedge.",
D: "Warp",
answer: "A. cotton",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. The ancient Egyptians usually made their garden",
A: "at backyards.",
B: "in courtyards.",
C: "at down stairs.",
D: "on rooftops.",
answer: "B. in courtyards",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. The organization of the elements gives an artwork its",
A: "Parts",
B: "principles.",
C: "proportion.",
D: "structure.",
answer: "D. structure",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. In a good composition, the negative and positive areas are rendered",
A: "balance",
B: "receding",
C: "formal.",
D: "solid",
answer: "A. balance",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Nomoli figures are mainly carved from",
A: "granite.",
B: "quartz.",
C: "sand stone.",
D: "soap stone.",
answer: "D. soap stone",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Identify the lettering without ornamental projections at the top and bottom ends of letters.",
A: "Calligraphy",
B: "Gothic",
C: "Freestyle",
D: "Italics",
answer: "C. Freestyle",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Historic era of civilization started when",
A: "happenings were told and written down.",
B: "fairy tales were told",
C: "important events happened",
D: "languages were invented and developed",
answer: "A. happenings were told and written down",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. The techniques of engraving used by the cavemen were",
A: "cutting and pecking.",
B: "painting and cutting.",
C: "etching and painting.",
D: "pecking and etching.",
answer: "A. cutting and pecking",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},


]